## Lucas J. Sterzinger

Curriculum Vitae

## Personal contact info removed for publication on GitHub https://github.com/lsterzinger

### INTEREST STATEMENT

I am an Atmospheric Science PhD candidate at UC Davis in my final year of studies. My research thus far has focused on numerical modelling of clouds and precipitation processes. I am passionate about open source and open science, and I have recently been involved in the development of Kerchunk, a software package aimed to make existing cloud-hosted datasets more accessible.

### **EDUCATION**

PhD, Atmospheric Science University of California, Davis, Davis, CA Anticipated Graduation: Fall 2022

Bachelor of Science, Atmospheric Sciences University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Aeronautics University of North Dakota, Grand Forks, ND

**TECHNICAL** 

Languages & Software: Python, Julia, Fortran Operating Systems: Unix/Linux, MacOS, Windows Software Packages:

- PyRAMS (maintainer) Package for working with RAMS model data
- Kerchunk (contributor) Cloud performant access to NetCDF4 data

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Do arctic mixed-phase clouds sometimes dissipate due to insufficient aerosol? Evidence from comparisons between observations and idealized simulations (In Review) Sterzinger, L. J., Sedlar, J., Guy, H., Neely III, R., & Igel, A. L. Atmospheric Chemistry and Physics https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-2022-36

### The Effects of Ice Habit on Simulated Orographic Snowfall

Sterzinger, L. J., & Igel, A. L. - Journal of Hydrometeorology https://doi.org/10.1175/JHM-D-20-0253.1

Models in the Cloud: A Cost Exploration of Cloud Computing for the Atmospheric Sciences News@Unidata Blog

https://www.unidata.ucar.edu/blogs/news/entry/models-in-the-cloud-a

2017 - Present

2012 - 2017

2012 - 2017

2021

Nov. 2017

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Graduate Student Researcher

Atmospheric Science Graduate Group, UC Davis

Dr. Adele Igel, Faculty Advisor

- Works on various research related to cloud and precipitation physics. Projects include:
  - Effect of ice crystal habit (shape) on orographic snowfall in the Sierra Nevada Mountains.
     (Funding: Internal)
  - Examining the relationship between mixed-phase Arctic cloud dissipation and aerosol properties. (Funding: DOE ASR; A. Igel, PI)
  - Assessing relative impacts on aerosol contained within the boundary layer and free troposphere
    on the microphysics and other properties of Arctic mixed-phase clouds. (Funding: DOE ASR;
    A. Igel, PI)

Intern Summer 2021

Summer Internship in Parallel Computational Science (SIParCS) National Center for Atmospheric Research (NCAR), Boulder, CO

- Worked with Chelle Gentemann (Farallon Inst.), Kevin Paul (NCAR), Julia Kent (NCAR), Rich Signell (USGS) and Martin Durant (Anaconda Inc.) on the development of the Kerchunk software library and its applicability and performance accessing cloud-hosted NOAA/NASA satellite data.
- Wrote documentation, blog posts, and example code on how to get started using Kerchunk published open-source on GitHub.

### Undergraduate Research Assistant

2016 - 2017

2017 - Present

Dept. of Atmospheric Sciences, University of N. Dakota

Dr. Gretchen Mullendore, Faculty Advisor

• Worked on the "Big Weather Web" project examining potential uses for cloud computing infrastructure for numerical weather prediction.

### Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

2015 - 2017

Dept. of Atmospheric Sciences, University of N. Dakota

Independently taught Introduction to Meteorology lab, complete with weekly lectures and laboratory experiments.

### Technical Support Specialist

2012 - 2017

Univ. of N. Dakota School of Medicine and Health Sciences

• Responsible for direct technology support to faculty, staff, and students. Also worked on managing video conference sytems, networks, and servers.

### **SERVICE**

### UC Davis Graduate Student Association

• General Assembly Representative

2019-2022

• Elections Committee

2019-2020

## UC Davis Academic Senate Committee on Information Technology

Graduate Student Representative

2020-2021

# **MEMBERSHIPS**

American Meteorological Society American Geophysics Union European Geosciences Union

# LANGUAGES

English French (Bilingual Fluency) German (2 years of courses)